Juan Pablo Poittevin Santana

Development Manager at Trafilea

juanpaps03@gmail.com

Summary

I'm a Django developer with over 6 years of experience in designing, building and deploying full stack solutions.

Currently leading the IT Team at Trafilea, I have plenty of experience developing web systems for customers around the world. I manage a versatile engineering team while seeking opportunities to learn the latest technologies.

Specialties:

- * Python Django developemnt
- * Project management
- * Team leadership
- * Cloud and distributed computing
- * Database management and software
- * Web architecture and development frameworks
- * Server deployment and management
- * Unix systems
- * Virtualization
- * Agile methodologies
- * Amazon web services infrastructure

Experience

Development Manager

noviembre de 2017 - Present

CTO at Innuy | Full stack development

abril de 2015 - Present

As the Company's CTO, I'm responsible for the study of new technologies, leading and working close to the IT team to increase their skills, general quality & professionalism. My responsibilities also include supervising the recruitment process, improving the development workflow and assisting the developers to achieve their goals with maximum efficiency possible. I ensure that the team is up to date with the best practices of each area and get new employees up to speed with the company's tech stacks.

Web Developer at Innuy | Full stack development

marzo de 2012 - abril de 2015 (3 años 2 meses)

During this time I specialized in Python Django and worked with various technologies like NoSQL Databases, RestFul APIs, HTML, CSS, AWS infraestructures, Big Data, Unix systems, on projects of very diverse size and requirements. This revealed my passion for building scalable and maintainable platforms. While I was growing professionally I also helped consolidate partnerships for the company, providing attentive and timely help for both our customers and team members, which consolidated my future position as CTO.

Education

Universidad de la República

Computer Engineering, 2014

Universidad ORT Uruguay

Object Oriented Programming, 2010 - 2012

Liceo Carlos Vaz Ferreira, Montevideo, Urugay

Diversified Baccalaureate, Engineering, 2009 - 2013

Juan Pablo Poittevin Santana

Development Manager at Trafilea

juanpaps03@gmail.com



Contact Juan Pablo on LinkedIn